Podcasting 2.0 for January
29th, 2021, episode 22,
this train is rolling down some
imaginary tracks, like Ruby on Rails.
It's Friday once again,
time for a board meeting of the
Podcast Index Podcasting 2.0 project.
I'm Adam Curry in Austin, Texas,
and now the man who spends $16 to
learn 64 new languages, Dave Jones.
I like it when you make
developer jokes. That's good.
Well, you know, I'm
basically a developer hag.
Yeah, that's like me
making philosophy jokes.
Yes, precisely.
In college, my short time that I spent
in college, I was a philosophy major.
Oh, really?
I was, yes.
How long did you last?
About two years.
Oh, man, I did three months. That was it.
Yeah, it was about a year and a half
longer than I expected the last,
but I gave it a good, I have willpower.
I'm like, all right, I think, I
like the communication classes,
I like the broadcast
classes, and I'm like,
but I'm already running the radio station,
and everyone's running around
smoking weed and drinking beer.
I come from Amsterdam.
I don't need this shit.
Yeah, that was like, you know, back
when I was in school, I was like 94,
and so that was going to be, like, I
was a cis admin already as a day job,
and I was like, I'm not learning anything
here that's going to help me put food on
my table, and I've already
got a wife and a kid coming.
I'm like, this, nah, it's not working.
Oh, man, shotgun wedding, huh?
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
I heard about you guys down south.
With the angry dad with the gun?
Oh, yeah, oh, yeah.
Well, it's time for our board meeting.
How are you, Dave?
How was the week?
It's doing pretty good.
It's a little busy, but it's doing fine.
Has AP written an article
yet about how podcasting
allowed the GameStop thing to happen?
I think the sequence is as follows.
First, we have to determine that
they were obviously alt-right,
white nationalist, Nazi, KKK, quadroons,
racists, who voted for Donald Trump.
Then, then we can say,
and they have podcasts.
Yeah, that's right.
And they radicalize, they self-radicalize.
That's right, that's right.
Yeah, and they listen to the Orange
Pill podcast with Max Keiser, and ooh,
and they're building secret
systems with Podcasting 2.0.
Oh, yeah, there's a tag.
There's a tag for that.
They got tags.
You're going to short
GameStop with your tags.
So, I made my developer
joke about languages,
but I think it's kind
of a big deal, I think.
You did something with language,
which I just saw some responses
from a couple of the developers.
I'm like, okay, whatever
you're doing here is good.
Oh, yeah, thanks.
Well, you know, part of the issue that we've
seen with the language stuff in the RSS
is that not all the,
well, a couple of things.
Not all the podcast feeds
specify the language element.
Ah.
And then, if they do,
they're not always accurate.
And so, I figured it's best to try
to, like, at the very beginning,
when I was first designing the database,
the table schema, I said, okay,
there's going to be a language.
And the news is going to be an issue.
There's going to be a language field,
and then there's going to be a detected
language field, or language detected.
Uh-huh.
And so, that language detected field in the
news feeds table has been sitting there
just unused for months now.
And so, I finally got around to doing the
work to get it, to get that thing rolling.
And so, there's going to be, what it's
doing right now is it's going through,
and it's just categorizing each
language that it detects in the feed.
Uh-huh.
And so, there'll be, in the
API responses, in the future,
once this process finishes, in API
responses, there'll be both of those fields.
There'll be a language and a detected
language that's going to be returned.
Ah, very nice.
Yeah, maybe it was the international devs
who were like, oh, this is nice, finally.
Yeah, I think there's a lot.
So, what prompted me to start to kind of
pick this ball up was I've gotten like two
or three emails over the last couple of
months from people from other podcast
platforms, not hosting platforms,
but just like guys that do audio
work in the podcast world.
And they have, and all three of
them have asked me, have said,
somebody told me about y'all's work,
and I'm wondering how much data you
have around languages and podcasts.
Huh.
And so, and I don't know why
this is a thing right now.
Somebody can enlighten me maybe, but,
you know, it was enough of, well,
everybody's asking about this.
I mean, it's not got to be that hard.
So, I'm just going to do that, and then
I'm going to dump out the next feed dump.
Well, this, let's look at it this way.
People has different portals
per country, obviously.
Mm-hmm.
So, I can see where someone presenting
something in a different country might want
to be able to highlight the
language of that country,
no matter what their project is.
I don't know.
Do you remember the guy that gave us
a list of podcasts from Kazakhstan?
Yeah, of course.
Yeah.
I listen to all of them.
They're great.
They're groovy.
Yeah, he was highlighting the
issue with having, you know,
in Kazakhstan, they have whatever.
Oh, funky-ass characters.
Well, no, no.
He was saying that they had two
language, two primary languages.
They had Kazakh and Russian.
And so, even though you
have the same country,
there's like two major
languages spoken there.
Right, right.
And just so that a podcast is from
Kazakhstan doesn't mean it's going to be a
particular language.
So, the language actually
becomes pretty critical.
Yeah, yeah.
Or, you know, whoever wants to pay us more,
Putin, we'll just change the language.
You guys can't have Kazakh.
Oil money.
I'm on oil.
You will take some of that.
I've got two, and this
is completely off topic,
but I just heard this on
the way home for lunch.
One phrase that irritates the hell
out of me is, does that make sense?
I don't know why.
I think I sometimes say that to you.
I say it, too.
Oh.
I think that's what irritated me is I heard
it, and I was like, God, it's annoying.
And I was like, wait, I
did that this morning.
I hate that I do that.
Why?
What's wrong with it?
Does that make sense?
I mean, that's asking someone for their
opinion, for their input, for their…
Because I think it's filler.
It becomes like, you know, or right.
And I need to be efficient
in my life, damn it.
I listen to podcasts at double speed.
Get to the point, people.
Tell me what you want.
It's as annoying to me as, like, far left,
far right, mid-center right, center left.
Yeah, I hear you.
Well, I have lots of things
like that that irritate me.
Sure.
Anyway.
But that's not important.
That's not important right now.
No, it's just talking about language
that brought that up in my head.
Yeah, I know.
I'm just doing an important just
because I like doing it that way.
No, I think we're… No, I think we'll
have a pretty good… I'm just watching.
I've been going through there
and I've been spot checking.
So, like, every… I don't know.
I'll just eyeball it once in a…
You know, once every hour
or so and grab a couple
of them and make sure that it's not
detecting some crazy language.
Right.
That's not true.
Yeah, but it's pretty…
It's been dead on accurate so far.
Anyway, it's going.
I think we're going to have something
pretty nice when it's finished.
Cool.
I heard on Pod News, Cridland,
he says 5% of all the feeds
he has in his database are
podcasting 2.0 compliant.
That seems low to me.
I don't know.
Really?
Yeah.
That actually have it?
No, I don't know.
Of all the podcasts?
Well, I mean, you've got… Let's see.
Shit, 5… I was happy with 5%.
I'm like, okay, that's a real start.
Let me see.
What… So, I mean, Buzzsprout
themselves have 80-something
thousand Podcast 2.0 enabled feeds.
Right.
So, what's 5% of 1.5?
300,000.
No, that's too much.
30,000?
I'm really bad at this.
All right.
Me too.
So, 10% would be 170,000, right?
That would be 10%.
And 5% would be 35,000.
75,000.
I'm sorry.
Yeah.
So, it's just Buzzsprout.
There you go.
We've solved the riddle.
See, that's the thing is it's not.
It's not just Buzzsprout.
It's also Fireside.
And it's also… I don't…
Well, someone's jacking
us with their numbers.
Yeah, Cridlin.
What are you doing?
What are you doing, Cridlin?
Get us some… What this always does,
you've got to be careful because
this will spawn five new threads,
arguments from every
hoster about who has more.
Arguments.
Oh, yeah.
Hosing arguments.
Spats.
Hey, congratulations to Podstation.
Yeah, yeah.
Integrating value for value with
the Keysend with streaming sats.
Very cool.
I have a lot of UX ideas, of course.
And the minute I'm using it, I'm like,
I'm not getting the satisfaction.
Why am I not getting the satisfaction?
It's because I'm not seeing a counter.
You know, when you're in Sphinx chat,
you see the sats go down every minute.
And that's even not the way I want it.
It's not as satisfying.
But when I popped open the log,
and for those who don't know,
Podstation is a Chrome plug-in.
And it's lickety-split very fast.
And it's always there in my browser menu.
So whenever I'm doing something
in the studio, it's real easy.
Like, pop.
Okay, I got this.
Lickety-split.
Sorry.
Boomer.
Boomer language.
My wife makes fun of me for
saying Johnny on the spot.
So you pop open the log,
and you see the payments.
And you see it accruing,
the number of payments.
And something about it
was really exciting.
And of course, I'm sitting
there with my own podcast.
I'm looking at my own wallet,
like, oh, there it goes.
I'm paying myself.
Oh, it's so cool.
Oh, look at it coming in.
You're going to go blind.
That's right.
Satoshi Nakamoto comes around
and pokes your eyes out.
Also, congrats to Podverse 3.0 in beta.
Tried it out today on Graphene OS.
Yeah, it's because you're on Android.
I got screwed because I
can't try to install it.
And he gave it to me and then
jerked the rug out from under me.
What happened?
He said they're not ready for iOS yet.
They're waiting on App Store
approval or something like that.
Of course.
Yeah.
The Indian giver.
Oh, wow.
Racist much, Dave Jones, man.
You sure you have young kids?
I mean, how come they're not busting
your ass on this kind of language?
Is Indian giver?
Has that been taken away?
Oh, my God.
No, yeah.
I'm sure that's taken away.
It implies that Native
Americans are cheats.
You're a racist, too.
It's not Native Americans.
It's indigenous peoples.
Actually, American Indians is
how they prefer to be called.
I have on good authority.
Oh, okay.
Well, we're all wrong.
Yeah, and everything I see is
they like Washington Redskins.
It's like, hey, we had a team.
And no more.
Anyway.
Oh, yeah.
I heard that, too.
No team for you.
Yeah.
Shut up.
But it's great.
Real fast.
Real simple.
They have the chapter images integrated.
Super slick.
Oh, nice.
It's on default.
So when you're playing the episode, it
shows you the time code from when to when.
It'll display, and then
it pops the next one.
I didn't see any way to jump,
which tickled my fancy.
I didn't see a way to get the full
list of chapters to jump around,
which is not how I want
people to use it anyway.
But that I couldn't find.
And they don't have transcript in.
They just ran out of screen real estate.
So you were happy for lack of a feature.
Oh, yeah.
Groovy.
If it's in there, keep it hidden.
I don't want people jumping around.
Yeah.
But I love the transcript.
And not so much because I need
to see what's being said.
But for the like what pod friend has is,
you know, you can search the transcript.
You have this is a a
major, major lifesaver.
So often someone will say
or even I'm thinking,
can we talk about that or
more more to the point?
My co-host, John C.
Devorak, will say, no, I never said it.
That's exactly how he sounds.
That is a true representation.
Yes.
And so that I can at least find if
I kind of know the general episode,
I can find stuff
on bingit.io, which is our search
engine that looks to the show notes.
OK, here's the topic.
What episode was it?
Go to the episode.
Click on the search.
Boom.
And Tom Schuring, who's in Australia,
who I've known for decades.
He's my official digital archivist.
He has been doing he's been
backdating archives of all the shows.
And so no agenda specifically.
He's been uploading them to otter dot A.I.
And he's building a search engine of
the entire transcripts of the show,
which is now, you know, one thousand
three hundred and sixteen transcripts.
So there's a lot of cool shit you can do.
And what's cool about it is, you know, we
have protocols, you know, we have SRT.
And so it's easy to shuttle
things around and, you know,
kind of what's expected and more
people can contribute to that work.
It's I find that incredibly useful
because the number one thing they say,
yeah, I was on that show.
And it's like two or three hours.
Like, you're not going
to go skipping around.
It's easier to just type in
some words and you're there.
If he needs my stop word
list for the people search,
I'll be glad to give it to him because
that that can that can
give you some real juice.
Oh, well, I'm sure he listens.
So I'm sure he'll like
because I've been thinking
about somebody sent me an email asking
about just general episode search.
So once the once the person tag
gets baked in, that's so good,
we'll be able to flip the
person search to use the person tag.
Nice.
But then we still need we still
need like a general episode search.
And so, like, I'll just
turn the person search
into a general episode
search because here's
like I find myself searching using
the using the person search,
but just putting in other
stuff that I know are not people's names.
And it like it gives me a bunch of
good a good, you know, criteria,
like a bunch of good results.
So like things like the word podcasting is
not in the the stop the stop word list.
So I get that'll return.
Right.
So if I put in like podcasting L&D
or something like that, you know,
you're going to get some
hits from other things.
Sure.
Yeah.
I know.
It's not sorcery.
I understand.
You can only do so much.
But it's help.
But it's helpful.
Like and so like if we
had the general what I'm
doing is resisting the urge to to go and
put and put all that stuff in the freedom.
Yeah.
And and I'm going to try and help you
resist what what seems to me, you know,
look, Apple is doing on the fly
transcription or at least they say they are.
Everyone's going to be doing
on the fly transcription
so they can help you find shows.
It seems to me that now
that we have kind of a
standard and SRT is the one that
I've seen applied the most.
Yeah.
Daniel J.
I hear you.
It should all be JSON.
I know.
But we just happen to have this.
It seems like such an
opportunity for someone
to create another project
that's not you and
I, Dave, another project
which is podcast transcripts
and you can just upload
your transcripts or
it'll automatically pull in from
your feed if you have them included,
which is the way to go.
And that will be a kick ass search engine.
Some search nuts will have so
much fun with that like you.
So that's why I'm really going
to try and help you resist.
They would have a lot of fun with that
because that is where all the juice is, man.
Well, like pod.
OK, so here's an example.
Here's something for pod verse.
Mitch, do do the value, do the
value blog, do the lightning stuff,
because when you have
clips that is that is a
way to not only fund pod
verse with with your one percent off that,
but also to that's a
that's a money machine for
the for podcasters that if they have good
content and that content
gets clipped a lot.
Think about me.
You know, we've talked about before,
like the clipping and sound
bites and those kinds of
things are like they're like
the hand claps on medium.
Yeah, yeah, exactly.
Like like hearts, hearts, hand claps.
Yeah.
But you get paid.
But in this but in this
scenario, you get paid for it.
Yeah.
Beautiful.
You're not just clicking a
stupid icon on a Web site.
You're actually like there's
real value behind that.
Along those lines, just as a as a side
note, you'll be talking this morning.
We had a Zoom call with
the executive director of
Ronald McDonald House
Charities Central Texas
where Tina used to work.
She was chief marketing,
chief communications officer.
And because of all the people that
are moving to Austin, you know,
we've got Oracle and Tesla
and Apple people and Google
and God knows what else.
And basically, California.
Yeah.
To your detriment.
We have a very two to the best children,
pediatric surgeons in the United States.
And so it's a very popular place to come
to, to Austin Dell Children's mainly.
And the Ronald McDonald House,
for those who don't know it,
what they do is they offer rooms
and, you know, kitchen and food and
Internet and, you know, computers,
whatever you need
and privacy and all kinds of stuff
and a sense of community, really,
at the house where you can stay.
And there's no charge for anybody, whether
you're a billionaire or off the street.
And, you know, they do suggest if you
can, you know, toss us 40 bucks a day.
Anyway, so they need to add.
They have 23 rooms now that
they're going to add, I think,
65 and they need $30 million.
And in the next two years, over
the next two years, I said, well,
I promise you this is that I'm
going to put you in my value block
and I'm going to set you up with
a wallet and, you know, and I'll,
and I know the, I'll know everybody there.
So I'll set up the CFO
and, and, and, you know,
whenever someone listens to
any of my shows, you know,
piece of my action is going
to go straight to you guys.
And they're like, really, you can do that?
Oh, yeah.
That's so cool.
And I thought, you know, if you go to
podcasterwallet.com in the future,
just as an idea, I'm, I'm, this
is not something we should do.
Um, I can easily see where there
would be a box that said, Hey,
do you want to add something for a
couple of charities or for a charity?
You want to add one for your own charity,
but we could have pre-populated,
uh, nodes drop down.
That's a great idea.
Isn't that cool?
Yeah, it does.
It's just like the checkout line
at the, at the grocery store.
Exactly.
That's super cool.
Like, okay, for, well, I've got, I'll, uh,
I see you're running a McDonald
house and I, and I raise you a,
a Birmingham civil rights Institute.
I mean, when you start tackling,
we, we went there on MLK day.
Like, uh, well, I got that
day off, uh, this year.
And so, uh, on Martin Luther King's,
uh, it was his birthday, I guess.
On Martin Luther King's birthday,
we went, uh, me and my wife,
my wife is very, she's very involved
with, um, uh, civil rights, uh,
activism and that kind of thing.
And so she said, why don't we all go to
the Birmingham civil rights Institute?
Cause I'd never been,
she's been many times.
And so, um, and this is a
treasure that like, no,
so few people know about
it's, uh, it's downtown.
And so we're, it's only just
a few blocks away from me.
We went and, uh, you know,
spent half a day there just going
through it and it's so good.
It's just, it just chronicles
all of Jim Crow and, uh, uh,
and all the civil rights activism.
Cause you know, Birmingham,
Alabama was just like ground zero.
Oh, totally ground zero.
And, uh, every, everything was racist.
Yeah.
We invented racism.
You're very good at it.
I love that you're now
married to Melissa X.
That makes it that much better.
Melissa X.
I got to tell her you said that.
Please do.
I love her.
Yeah.
She, uh, but she's like, let's go.
And so we went and we spent half
the day and I was thinking there,
like they go through all
these, um, you know,
it's like room by room and you have
narration narrators and that kind of thing.
I was thinking, man, it would be so
good if this place had had a podcast,
did a podcast and I'm,
I'm fired up now after
hearing you talking about
that to help them start a podcast and
then, and put the value block in it.
Sure.
Um, that's the funding that
that's, that's awesome.
And the more you think about digital
money, the more excited you get, the more,
and just even this very simple,
um, process that we've invented.
And I'll say that we invent, you know,
royalties aren't new, but this idea is,
and, uh, and the
idea that you can change your royalties
easily, uh, your royalty structure.
Um, I mean, you could even do this with
multi-seg wallets, so it can't change list.
You have two or three or five of seven.
I mean, there's so many
different things you can do.
It just is mind boggling, mind boggling.
And shout out to Ryan Gentry for mentioning
us in the lightning labs newsletter.
That was very cool.
That was a good blog post.
Yeah.
Our names are Adam Curry and Dave
Jones, but otherwise, thanks, man.
Yeah, douche.
Thanks, Ryan.
Uh, we're going to get to
our guests momentarily
who have been patiently
waiting in the wings.
Um, I wonder what that's like.
I mean, typically on a
show, like, I guess they,
they interview right away and they cut
it in later and we just force our guests
to listen to our crap for 20 minutes.
It's, it's, it's building pent
up demand, so it just unleashes,
unleashes creative energy.
It really does.
And, uh, and I can't wait to do some hot
namespace talk with these two gents.
Uh, we have the co-founders
of rss.com podcasting, uh,
with us here on podcasting 2.0.
We have Alberto Betela and
Ben Richardson, gentlemen.
Hey guys.
Hello.
Did I pronounce that
right, Alberto Betela?
That was perfect.
Alberto is from Italy originally.
He's one of those radicals
from, uh, from, uh, Barcelona.
A mix of Italian and Spanish.
I mean, not Barcelona.
What do I say?
I'm really confused.
Your sister lives in Italy.
Catalonia.
That's what I was, that's
what I wanted to say.
Catalonia.
Yeah.
Those guys.
Where's Willow?
She's in, Willow's in Italy.
Yeah.
My sister is in Firenze.
Oh.
All right.
Now I have to ask.
This will be great.
Have you ever heard?
Of Alessandro Paci?
Oof.
I, I, I don't think so.
Okay.
It seems like a common
surname, but I, I don't.
I don't know.
He's a, he's a comedian.
And, uh, I guess he did like
some famous Italian movie that,
that kids pass around about
Pinocchio, only it's the
X-rated version of Pinocchio.
Does this ring a bell?
I heard something about
that, but I never saw it.
See, I see.
I'm telling you, my boy is famous.
It's the X-rated Pinocchio.
Yeah.
The only thing you know about, uh, about
a culture that's not American, Dutch,
is their, is their porn.
It's not porn.
It's like, it's kind of
like, it's like faces.
Remember faces of death?
And these guys are too young.
I'm sure.
Oh yeah.
I remember that.
Faces of death.
Big regret of my life.
Yeah, man.
Like we had the VHS and was the 20th copy.
And some guys, some guys had a Betamax.
It was, oh, it's better quality.
And, uh, or Phillips 2000.
I had a copy on Phillips 2000.
That was the great system.
And, and it was just all these
horrible ways that people die.
And, you know, and everyone always
was like, dude, dude, wait for it.
When you wait until they eat the
monkey brains at the end, you know?
So the guy got pulled, he got his
arms and legs drawn and quartered.
This is so cool.
Man, you just brought up
some repressed memories.
I need to loosen you guys up.
I need to get you ready.
Yeah.
And you, yeah, we had a buddy
that's like, it's real, man.
I swear.
I swear it's all real.
Yeah.
So these guys are OG, uh, to
the space and the industry.
Alberto goes back to shit, man.
Almost the beginning to 2004, 2005.
Is that where you guys started out?
Or did you meet later on?
What happened?
Oh yeah.
So 2005, uh, we met,
uh, uh, we met in 2017.
Oh crap.
Okay.
No, all right.
But that, but we, we go back a few years.
All right.
Yeah.
Alberto's, uh, he's OG in the
sense that, uh, when he was doing,
I think his master's thesis,
his professor said, Hey, I
want to syndicate my lectures.
Can you build me a podcast?
This is what I've been dreaming of.
Yeah.
So, uh, so yeah, 2005,
he built that for his professor and
then turned it into podcast generator,
uh, and then put it open source.
Cause he's a very sharing guy.
And, uh, so that's when he got started.
Yeah.
That's so the thesis, but
Alberto, this thesis, I got it.
I just got to read this title.
Okay.
From effective, from effective
computing to empathic adaptive systems,
inference and induction
of emotion in ecologically
valid context to foster
novel paradigms of human
computer interaction.
Now, look, listen, that is
clearly about sex robots.
I was going to, that is so hot.
I mean, I agree.
That's exactly the, the,
the topic of the thesis.
Did you read it?
Uh, no, I can't read it.
I can't find it.
It's, it's locked behind a million
academic journal paywalls.
No, but that, that, that, that thesis,
uh, it comes later, uh, actually in 2005,
I was still in Italy in the small
university of Bergamo in the,
in the North close to Milan.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
And, uh, and yeah, and then that,
that my, my supervisor told me,
why don't we do university podcasting?
And I said, pod what?
And then I searched and
I found the two names.
I thought I found the
Adam Carey and the one.
And I said, okay, okay.
That's what podcasting is.
And we launched, uh, an
educational podcasting in, in,
in the university 2000 in 2006 and
the engine called podcast
generator was released
open source and it's still alive today.
It's a, it's a CMS for,
for podcast publishing.
Thank you.
Wow.
And so is the, is the, now rss.com,
is it based on that original
code or just the, the, whatever
concepts or how much of that
is, uh, is in your, is,
is floating around legacy in your life.
So the first version, the MVP
that we launched, uh, uh,
in early 2018 was based
fully on podcast generator.
Ben and I met before and we said, okay,
let's try, uh, let's try to maybe Ben,
you can, you can introduce how
you, how did you reach out to me?
Yeah.
So, um, I, I was running rss.com
with a feed reader on top, uh,
based off of Ben Ubo's
feed bin and swimming against the
current, uh, for RSS readers.
Um, but I kept getting customer
support requests asking, you know,
how do I get my podcast feed?
And I was like, what are these people,
you know, maybe I need to, you know,
satisfy some demand here.
So this was already a company.
You were already providing services.
Yeah.
I had a feed reader on it.
Um, and you know, it was a great product,
but just not commercially
viable in many respects.
And so after a while, I thought I just
should find a way to help people podcast.
And, um, I looked for, you know,
something that was open source immediately
honed in on podcast generator.
I read up on Alberto a little bit.
He, I saw, he spoke, uh,
English, Italian, and Spanish,
and I speak English, Italian, and Spanish.
And so I sent him a quick note, just hoping
somehow he would reach back out to me.
Um, and he did, he, uh, he wrote
back and said, let's talk.
And he's like a three letter domain,
you know, that's, that's awesome.
Yeah.
And so it was, it was enough, it was
enough, uh, to pique his interest.
And, um, you know, we just started talking
about, you know, what it could be.
And, you know, Alberto, uh, was the
CTO of a successful, um, mobile app,
uh, at the time.
And, uh, so yeah, anyway,
we got talking about a side project
and he just said, let's put
podcast generator out there, um, on
the cloud and let's see what happens.
And it just kind of took off.
Knowing a thing or two about domain
names, when did you acquire rss.com?
Were you the first to register?
No, I was not the first to register.
I, I got, uh, rss.com from Ron Sheridan
back in 2013 and, uh, Ron, uh,
I don't know his middle name.
Maybe he got it, uh, originally.
I'm not sure.
I think it was registered, um,
towards the late nineties, but,
or maybe it was, yeah, early.
I don't remember.
So you paid big money for it or it was,
it was not the cheapest thing
I've ever done in my life.
I've, I've, I've, I've, I've,
uh, traded a couple in and, uh,
had some lawsuits over others.
Yeah.
Well, so, you know that, you know, yeah.
So, um, I had to research the legalities,
uh, pretty heavily before, um,
jumping in, but it was, uh,
yeah, it was serendipitous.
I mean, I knew I wanted to put
something on there that was an end use.
Cause I think Weiner got a
million bucks for weblogs.com.
Now his timing was impeccable.
Yeah.
It's gotta be usually.
That was very good.
And, uh, I once got a bud.com,
uh, for my client Budweiser.
No, I, I, I didn't have it.
My client was Budweiser and we
were putting them on the internet.
We built all their websites and he had,
and this old geezer who was just
a fan of the beer had bud.com.
And, uh, and so they called us and, you
know, how do we get this from this guy?
I said, well, let me talk to him.
So he called them up and said, Hey ma'am,
you're putting this on the internet.
Oh, that's so cool.
So, you know, but you know, bud.com, you
know, you of course have your rights,
but man, they
would really, uh, really appreciate if we
can come to some kind of understanding.
It's like, well, um, can I get a
case of long neck signed by, uh,
by August Bush the third?
I'm like, yeah, I think I
can erase that for you.
Yeah.
You took your marker out right there,
went down to the corner store
and sign them five cases.
We actually had, uh, the fourth, give
him a call to, you know, I was like,
you know, but the guy really didn't care.
He was just like, I love the brand.
I love it.
And the, and the idea that he got, you
know, signed and talked to, to Woody,
who was, uh, August Bush the fourth.
Um, it was great.
Yeah.
So yeah, it's, uh, fun, fun stuff.
That domain name is.
Yeah.
I mean, nowadays they'll send
you a, I can't remember.
It's a Uderp or usurp or whatever,
where, uh, you're not, you know,
commercially using it.
They'll, uh, they'll take you
down and take your domain.
Oh, really?
Who does this?
I mean, anybody can file with,
uh, if you're not using it.
Oh, really?
Well, no, you can be using it, but then,
uh, they can say, well, you're using it.
Uh, you shouldn't be, yeah.
And, and it's, my business
was, uh, you know,
came before yours and you're a squatter.
And I mean, you've got to
be really careful in this.
I've had curry.com for shoot, man, what?
30 years almost.
And, uh, and I get offers all
the time or no, I should say,
I get people saying, Hey,
what do you want for it?
Like, okay, delete.
Uh, from time to time,
someone will say 50 grand.
I'm like, no, man.
Yeah.
That's where I got, that's
where I got lucky with
Ron Sheridan is I reached out kind of like
that, um, and he, he wrote me back.
He's like, typically I wouldn't write
anybody back cause it's a bunch of idiots.
But for some reason I wrote you and I'm
like, well, this is, this means something.
Let's go, Ron.
Let's, you know, let's get this done.
So you guys teamed up and then,
uh, um, I mean, just tell me the,
how it went from there.
I mean, between then and now three, four
years, what's the path been for you guys?
Yeah.
So, well, when we teamed
up, we launched our MVP,
which was podcast
generator with a layer of,
payment layer on top of payment processor.
It was Stripe.
And for the first, uh, you know, year and
a half, we started growing, you know,
at the beginning, it was just Ben and
myself, uh, and it was a side project.
But then, uh, so we
launched in January, 2018.
And around summer, we got, uh,
Brian helping us with marketing
and especially with our blog
to write, uh, original content
to attract, uh, organically,
you know, possible users.
And then we got on board
the first engineer, David,
who started to help with both engineering
and customer support.
Nice.
Why do they need an engineer?
They got you.
Yeah, really?
What's wrong with that shit?
No, that's great.
So, yeah, Alberto's, uh, you
know, got a day job and plus.
Um, and, uh, so this is
like kind of been one
of those things that we can
get done on the weekends.
Uh, but fortunately he
has so many contacts.
Davide was, I think in either his
master's or his PhD program, um, and,
you know, they're good friends.
And so they were able to work together.
How much of, how much of podcast generator
code is still running, uh, RSS.com?
Today, zero, but until
January, uh, 2020 last year,
it was a whole podcast generator.
So for two years, we did a big,
uh, big, uh, big code revamp.
It was a monolith in digital ocean.
And we started to have podcasters, uh,
you know, at the beginning that grew,
one of them was bought
by sport, uh, Fox sport.
Right.
So when they would tweet, everything
would go, go down or systems down.
So we started working on.
Right, right, right, right, right.
Like the old days, man.
Perfect.
Yeah.
Good times.
But then we, we, we launched a great
platform, AWS, you know, uh, we, we,
we really worked on microservices.
Now we are, we are very
proud of the tech we have.
Um, so now we are very
happy with what we have.
Are you concerned at all?
Just hearing that, you know, you
rely at least partially on AWS,
that if there's someone who
has some content that's flowing through
your pipes that they don't like,
and they get, uh, someone gets all huffy.
I mean, dealing with that, have
you seen any cancel culture,
anyone coming to you and saying
you got to do something?
No, I mean, not, uh, on the U S side.
Anyway, we freak not frequently,
but occasionally we'll handle a
customer support request, come
in and take down somebody.
And, um, you know, I, uh, I, uh,
I think I side with most, uh,
podcast hosting companies.
It's just not, not a place
we want to wait into.
So AWS, uh, you know, we think they've got
a great product and that's what it is.
It's a product and we want to, you know,
offer our customers the greatest, uh,
you know, content
distribution, uh, that we can.
And so, yeah, AWS is going to
be who we're with, but I don't,
I don't think they want
to, um, you know, wait into the
weeds on this sort of stuff.
Well, I can only say from experience,
they do have a system because I got a,
I got a notification
once because of just
its index page for, uh,
no agendas archive and
someone issued, uh, you
know, that sent whatever
process there is at Amazon.
Somehow I got an automatic email that said,
okay, this is hosting a racist content.
And, uh, what do you say?
No, it was, uh, COVID
health misinformation.
Oh no, COVID health misinformation.
Thank you for correcting me.
Yeah.
Which is also racist, believe me.
Um, and, uh, and I just replied saying,
oh, this is just a list of links to, to
the individual show.
So I don't know what you're talking about.
And then it was like, thank you
for satisfying our request.
I mean, usually it's just people trying to
check the boxes, um, you know, because of
whatever sort of protocols
that they've put in place.
I love, I love reporting.
You know, I, I'm the admin for,
uh, no agenda social.com and,
and here's what people will report.
Cause I look at the reports.
So they'll see something on the,
on the public federated timeline,
which is like sticking
your head in a sewer, you
know, in a, in a sewage river.
That it's just scrolling by.
So, okay, you're, you're there, right?
I know you're there.
And then they'll see something, which
is, I mean, really rank, you know,
some, whatever porn picture it
is, but it's always obfuscated.
This is, this is what I like
about Mastodon is by default,
you can just have all of your
porn pictures fuzzed out.
So in order to see what's in the picture,
you have to actively click on it.
So, you know, people who actively click
on it and then go, oh no, and report it.
I'm like, what is wrong with you?
Don't click on it.
So weird.
You know, was it the wrong porn?
Maybe that's why they're reporting it.
I'm disgusted.
I expected something else.
It's misinformation.
They expected Pinocchio.
Yeah.
We want that.
We want that Pinocchio movie.
They're looking for your dissertation.
So you guys now are, you know,
we were talking before the show
and you mentioned that you're
up to like 12 employees.
I said, oh, well, that's a magic number.
Cause when you have 12,
you might as well have 20.
And so, you know, what are your plans?
I mean, do you, are you just going
to keep growing organically?
Are you thinking of, I don't know,
what do you, where are you at?
Because the space is
not big, but you know,
there's definitely competitors
and maybe people on the prowl.
Yeah, we are definitely growing.
We're growing a lot, but at the same time,
we live in a great time
in human history where
technology can help keep our
head countdown, should you say?
So, uh, I mean, the, the
scale is very manageable.
We, we, uh, Alberto and I
both have experience in, um,
managing large teams and this is not
something that we want to, I mean, we,
I wouldn't wish that on my worst enemy.
Um, so there, there has to be super
compelling reason to, to, you know,
increase the size of the team.
And so we're extremely selective,
um, and thankfully we can be, uh,
because we can, you know, project
our growth and we know exactly
what we need based on our product roadmap.
And, uh, so far so good.
So yeah, uh, hopefully we don't grow
headcount, but we're definitely growing, uh,
in all the other respects.
Cool.
Well, I mean, with product roadmap,
does the product roadmap include, uh,
tell me it includes the podcast namespace.
Hold on a second.
Hold on.
There we go.
It's time for some hot namespace.
Oh, I was waiting for you to rip
the clothes off of her, Dave.
Dave, thank you so much.
It's exactly what we need is some hot
namespace talk because these guys,
I don't think they're in our, uh,
cubby hole, so to speak, just yet.
No.
So we, we do include the
namespace and we already
have implemented and
rolled out the locked tag.
Ah, there it is.
I was waiting for the plan.
Hold on.
Let's just do it one more time
and just make sure we feel hot.
Yeah.
He's a dominatrix.
He's got us locked up with his lock tag.
We are, we are also sending all
our shows to podcast index.
I think from the, uh, the week.
Oh yes.
Yeah.
That's right.
You're updating.
Yep.
Absolutely.
Yeah.
And we are going to roll out.
Oh, thank, thank you for
creating podcast index.
Of course.
And, uh, we are also rolling out all the
next, uh, uh, let's say the next, uh,
tags, um,
in the, the ones that were approved in
phase one in the next couple of weeks in,
in, in, in our staging environment.
And we are, we are running QA cycles.
Oh no, no.
Hey, if anyone appreciates that this is
not a small undertaking, it's Dave Jones.
Uh, and I've, I've been
enough around enough to know.
So that's really cool.
I'm very happy to hear that.
That's very nice.
And I'm so happy that you're
doing the implementation
and it's as pleased as
I am that Libsyn has
opened something up to
allow people to do stuff.
Uh, and I'm not quite sure.
I haven't investigated myself yet.
Um, you know, the, the, the actual
implementation of the tags into the,
into the UI for your customers
is, is really appreciated.
Exactly.
You know what the challenge is there
was, uh, as you say, UI and UX.
Now our, uh, because we attract
most of our users organically,
we don't spend much in marketing.
We really, uh, we attract people
who are starting podcasting.
So, and we, we run a lot of
surveys, uh, with our users.
For example, the last one was, uh, uh,
um, let's say net promoter score survey.
Uh, and we got a thousand, 200 replies.
We got a great NPS and
also we got a word cloud
through hot chart about what they said.
Right.
Yeah.
And everyone is saying we,
you know, easy, simple.
So that's our, our, our
trademark if you want.
So our problem with all these tags was
how can we keep it easy and simple.
Yes.
So we are, we, we, we, we
will show it very soon,
but we have a way to fade in and fade
out tags and create an advanced
mode in a, in a, in a simple mode.
Oh, so the old advanced mode.
All right.
Turn the remote, turn the
remote control over granny.
Although we probably won't name it
advanced because it's not a problem.
Scare people.
Advanced mode is also
known as normal mode.
Right.
Yeah.
Advanced is the new normal, but
we are going to change the name,
but we are going to find
a way so that we introduce slowly to
new podcasters, all these options.
Otherwise they get overwhelmed.
So that, that's the result
of our U S research.
Yeah, this was a Tom Rossi at Buzzsprout
told me, he said, if you had, he said,
if you put a box on your UI, somebody's
going to stick something in it.
So you got to be really careful.
Hey, I can, I can paste something in here.
Yeah.
He's like, you gotta be real careful
when you put a box up there.
Yeah.
I always paste JSON, just throw
it in there everywhere I can.
My JSON aggregator.
On the phase two, on the phase two
stuff, this, uh, with podcasts, uh,
see person and
location, I mean, that'll be final,
that'll be sort of finalized and closed,
uh, on the 31st.
So a couple of days from
now, like what do y'all,
I'm guessing y'all are going to look
at those tags phase one first.
Yeah.
And then like person or location.
What do y'all think about those?
Yeah.
I mean, those are the ones
that get me super excited.
The phase two stuff.
Um, we talk about that all the time.
Um, you know, we, we
even at one point had a,
an intern that was a tour
guide in Madrid, Spain.
And I just keep, you
know, telling Alberta,
like we need to build
what Dave and Adam are
building and the other guys so
that she can like podcast her.
She didn't have to tour guide anymore.
She just builds a tour guide podcast.
So these things are cool.
Yeah.
You know, but even I'm, I see it so clearly
in my head and it goes back to what,
you know, to your history, Alberto
is, I've always wanted, um,
a lecturer professor to say, shit, I've
got a great course here.
I want to put it up and then it'd
be able to clickety, clickety,
clack upload done and
immediately turn around.
And it's available on a whole plethora
of apps with all kinds of options.
And at the same time, I think, you
know, a different UX, if you will,
needs to be created.
People who have different
needs, like, like, you know,
when I hear a location podcast, man,
I can envision a completely different
type of app that handles that in,
in a certain way.
I mean, you know, why wouldn't a map
be the main feature of the main page?
You know, um, as, as you hear the
audio, the map moves, I mean,
there's a million things
I can come up with.
I fully agree.
And actually the main, the main
challenge in implementing podcast index,
um, namespace is just
the UX in our opinion.
Yeah, of course.
So, yeah.
And, and, and so also, for example,
other, uh, other feature like, uh,
imaging donation through
lightning network, right?
Great idea.
It's not as simple as
having, for example, Stripe.
So the, ideally the user
doesn't want any friction.
They would like to just add their
credit card once and just click.
And then donations are, you know,
sent automatically every X minutes.
That's the UX layer that we have to
fine tune as a, as a, as a, you know,
in, in the field.
No, I understand.
And I think that that is, uh, what, um,
I love the way you're
talking about it because
the approach is correct.
In my opinion, a lot of, uh,
hosting companies have been the
tool and we've had a tool and
the tool worked pretty much
the same way for years.
The only additional tool we had was
some authoring tools, um, for, uh,
chapters in the file.
And that's about it.
Um, so now everyone is, and I understand,
you know, it's like, oh, now you're tasked
with, it's not a matter
of adding some tags.
You have to actually invent a tool because
yes, it is UX and it's not just a tag.
It's like, okay, how do I get someone
if they want to make chapters?
What is that experience like?
And yeah, that's hard.
That's really hard.
No one's done it.
No one has thought about it.
And I love that you guys are going
through that process in a structured way.
It sounds right.
Yeah.
And there is a topic here, for
example, the hosting itself.
So we don't like to be
labeled necessarily as
a hosting company because
we actually offer a tool.
Uh, I think you spoke perhaps the
last episode about the EPFS, right?
What happens if we start to host there?
Yeah.
I was going to bring that to you next.
Okay.
So that, that's the point, right?
So I thought about that when I
was listening to, to the episode,
I was speaking with Ben and
we said, if this happened,
we would leverage EPFS.
We would save a lot of money
in bandwidth for AWS, right?
That's right.
Yeah.
Because we, what we,
our value is in the tool and that's
why we want to keep it simple.
So hosting, podcast hosting, it's not
necessarily the best description of,
of what we feel we are
offering to our users.
Give me a description.
I'd love to use a different word.
Oh man.
We'll pay you for that word.
Okay.
I mean, I prefer content platform,
you know, it's content distribution.
It's it's, and that content.
So you want to cover the
entire supply user chain.
Hosting is just a small part of
that, but then you have to applaud,
you have to distribute.
And that's the whole point.
That's what we think.
Yeah.
It's really, it's really a podcast
design tool or designer suite.
Creation.
True.
Yeah.
Oh, I hate the word creation, by the way.
Why am I, why am I doing, okay.
You know what?
I will work on that.
And if I come up with something,
I will of course pass it on to you
and sometimes come up with stuff.
We got marketers in this house.
Um, at the same time, uh,
how can we work together to make your
bandwidth go away and how can we push IPFS?
What, what pieces do we need to
put in place to make this work?
And, and I, and I'm really
stepping out because
this is where the namespace
gets sizzling hot
because we have disagreements
over how to do this.
Yeah.
It's a complex question.
All right.
So what we're talking about is an
alternative enclosure in essence.
Exactly.
So that's the point.
Like, uh, perhaps, uh, the, the, uh, a
gradual shift would be the best option.
So you have an alternate enclosure.
So people wanted to use or leveraging
IPFS, even clients, right.
That use that, uh, would, would
go through that, uh, you know,
the file system and, uh,
the others would just go
through a normal CDN.
That, that would be my, my, my, my guess.
And that's the way I keep suggesting
it, but no one, no one loves me.
No one picks up on it.
They're like, man, I'm going
to shut up non-developer.
I don't know what you're talking about.
I mean, it's, it's, it's not so easy to
plug into IPFS, meaning there are a lot,
there are a lot of pieces
that have to fall into place.
Right, no, I'm just talking about
purely about where do you put this?
Where do you, how do you alert the
aggregator that there's an option?
And I, and I think what you
said is make it initially, uh,
a separate tag in the namespace.
Uh, but that, that I can't get anyone
to agree with me on that except you.
Or one tag, the enclosure tag with
another attribute, which is a IPFS.
Yeah, I think that's the argument.
And, and I don't know what it is.
I think people are
worried that X amount of
apps will not be able to understand it or
aggregators will puke over it.
I'm not sure.
Dave, Dave, way in here.
Well, I think when you, I'm
swimming, I'm drowning.
Yeah.
Um, I think what happens when you,
with this kind of stuff is
there's always a couple of
things that have, you don't want to
be tied to one specific protocol.
And so everybody immediately, when you
bring up, okay, let's do IPFS, uh,
it's like, yeah, but we
need to generalize this,
this tag to where it's not
just IPFS specific, because
what if we want to distribute
it over some other DHT?
And so like, then you get
into this flame, this,
this sort of back and forth debate about
how much to generalize it.
Because it's 20 years from now, if IPFS
was superseded by some other thing,
you don't
want some legacy, you know, thing just
hanging around this, that was too specific.
That seems like the argument
that you always get into.
And, but then you got to,
but I'm not so sympathetic to that because
you got to plant your flag somewhere.
I mean, RSS, uh, podcasting
wouldn't exist, uh, without,
without Weiner planting the flag
and saying, okay, and here's how we do it.
It has to be HTTP.
Yeah.
Well, I mean, you need someone
to go Leroy Jenkins on it.
Yeah, exactly.
Let's just do it.
You know, I mean, cause
we could, we can say,
we could spend a lot of time saying, well,
we need to make the value tag support,
uh, lightning, hive, web monetization,
blah, blah, blah, blah.
And I, and I'm sympathetic
to some of that and I,
and I want those things to happen, but
I don't want it to hold back things
to hold back the progress forward.
Well, you're the man, you're the
man with the keys in my mind.
I, I, it's my mission to convince
you and I have not done that yet.
So I don't know if you're just, if
you're waiting for the IPFS stuff.
No, just for alternative, you know, cause
another part of that conversation is,
uh, well, we want to be able to
do lower resolution for people
who live in Zimbabwe and
which is completely true.
I've, I've done that.
Uh, you know, we want torrents.
I, I, I get it all.
So we just have to figure
out what will work.
And I, and of course I agree
that in 20 years, if it's hive,
then it should be working with hive.
Um, you know, that's, that's
an obvious one, but to me,
I just feels like throw it in a namespace.
And, you know, if you've got an alternative
to me, it's an alternative right now.
And IPFS, here's how you address that.
And it's torrent.
Here's how you address that.
I mean, well, I don't think we
need to be afraid to, I think the,
the sort of the baseline
on that is we don't need
to be afraid to put things
in there that may ultimately fail because
I mean, there's things in the original
RSS aspect that aren't used anymore.
Of course, stuff that is misnomers.
Absolutely.
So can we, can we create
with a number of the RSS
platform tool creation hosting companies?
Can we create a consortium
of such of sorts
where we're all hosting gateways
and maybe pinning stuff?
I mean, uh, Ben, is this, uh, is there,
is there any crossover talk
or any real communication
with your, um, uh, frenemies?
Well, so I would call
them friends possibly.
I mean, so, um, yeah, I mean, so there
was, um, the first ever, um, the podcast,
uh, convention I went to
was right before COVID hit.
And, uh, I met, uh, Todd
from Blueberry there.
Um, and I got talking with him and was
super like, I almost relieved that, um,
I mean, he's an open guy.
I listened to his podcast now.
I love kind of learning from him.
Who's been in the space for
so long and the others,
I try to listen to as much as I can.
That said, um, you know, as I introduced
myself and talked to him, he said,
oh man, you should
have been at the RSS coalition meeting
we had, uh, before kickoff this morning.
They had great food.
Yeah.
The, the, the shrimp was delicious.
So, um, but that said, like, you
know, there's constantly, uh,
a demand or desire to get
everybody involved, but, um, it's extremely
difficult because we're fragmented,
um, through so many ways.
I mean, location, no, nobody's in
Silicon Valley that I'm aware of.
Um, you know, so creating a network,
the network effect is basically
going to revolve around,
you know, a Slack channel like
it was for RSS coalition.
Uh, but then there's no real drivers.
There's no, um, so how about this?
Cause it seems to me, and
I'm glad you said friends.
It seems to me that, and
maybe we kick this off.
I don't know.
And we can probably, we can
certainly, uh, help if every,
if all of the similar companies
or at least enough of them all
collaborate on an IPFS, uh, gateway.
So you're also pinning and
hosting for your colleagues.
I think you could, uh, all like rise your,
raise your bottom line by
maybe 20%, maybe more.
Yeah.
We could host it, right?
And we, we can host some
of, we can have a node.
We'll do a, I mean, Dave,
Dave seems to be able to run like
fucking Google on $300 a month.
I don't know how he does it, but Dave's
got all this wacky shit and it's like, Oh,
look, it costs six bucks for what?
No, for everything.
So there's, there's definitely, and I'm,
you know, you guys are in the band with the
game, so you understand it.
But if we kick that off, I mean,
would you be interested in
trying to figure this out?
Because it's the, and I understand
namespaces, all this stuff is slow,
all of it's slow, but
even just getting it started takes, you
know, a couple of people, you know,
and I think we,
we can help, you know, the first person
to jump in, we'll pin everything.
We'll do every, whatever we can.
Yeah.
I mean, before we get into the specifics
there, let me just take the moment to just
say, thanks for jumping in.
Like you guys, you know,
I was getting a little frustrated
with what I was reading on the RSS
coalition about, you know, how
we could improve the namespace,
but there was just never
really any movement.
And I just watched it
start to die before me.
And I had so much hope and I'm sure
everybody in there too felt like, you know,
Oh no, this is happening again.
We're not getting anywhere.
And I talked with James Cridland the
first time I ever talked to him,
I'm like, James,
this is not going to work out.
Like, what can we do?
And he said, Oh, just
wait till I do this, uh,
this release on Monday or
Tuesday, whatever it was.
And you're going to, you're going to
see that there's this podcast index.
He didn't even name it.
He didn't name it.
He was under embargo, but he's
like, you'll be surprised.
Did we ever embargo any one day?
Well, yeah, I told him
to shut the hell up.
No, that was last week.
No, no, no.
He was definitely not wanting
to Trump the news basically.
So, all right.
And so we waited and I
mean, that's, we, listen,
we were like your first fans just because
we knew what we were looking at.
You know, you guys have
supported us in ungodly ways.
And you really, you've, whatever
value you got, you have returned.
So we appreciate it.
This is a mutual love society.
We're happy to do it
because Alberto and I sat
around talking for at least two weeks.
Like, how can we improve?
I mean, and I know Todd had that same
conversation eight years before us.
I mean, it was just a continual problem.
Uh, and so we're happy
to support financially
just because we know the amount
of work that you saved us.
Like it literally, we were just staring
down the barrel of a, just now was that,
was that for the search
and the index part?
That's really where, were
we able to help you guys?
No, I mean, just in the, in the, um,
just in the namespace, like how,
how it's like got new life in it.
I mean, it's been resurrected almost.
We were looking at, you
know, what was, you know,
RSS feeds used to be in Facebook, for
instance, they're no longer there.
And as I was looking at the
silos that were happening
with Spotify kind of gobbling things
up and then killing off an RSS feed, like
I could just see the writing on the wall.
Like this is going to happen the same way
it's happened to all these other things.
You, you no longer have RSS access.
You have to go get API keys and then
that's the keys to the kingdom.
They can kick anybody out.
Like it was just going
to be a restriction.
On that note, Dave.
Yes.
API keys.
Quick mention.
Okay.
Go ahead.
It's your idea.
You're going to open it up.
Oh yeah.
Yeah.
We're, uh, we're, I've got some more
thinking to get to do on this, but we're,
I think, you know, we have talked
before when I hijack your brain.
Yeah.
You man, I have, I'm sitting here staring
at my dog trying to do something horrible.
Uh, but the, the, uh, remember he's
only doing it because he can Dave,
Dave, uh, he tries to
screw me at everything.
They, so the original idea was to take,
uh, was to go in the other direction.
So, uh, if we would say put the value
stuff, uh, into a higher, uh, higher key,
uh, permission level, then we started
thinking, you know, this looks,
it makes more sense going
the other, other direction.
So then we put the value, uh,
responses, value tag responses,
keep those in the API, just
like everything, just
like it is right now,
but then open the API to where anybody can
query it with, without API keys.
And for the very reason you just
mentioned, that's why I brought it up.
Yeah.
If we do it that way, then we're a
direct, um, what would you call it?
We're, we're a direct
alternative to an iTunes lookup
because they don't require API keys and
we get the benefit of
being able to cache the
heck out of everything with cloudflare.
So then we can, because what pro
what the problem is now with,
with caching is that if you have
a, if you have a, uh, a rotating
API access hash in your header,
everything has to come
through and hit the hardware.
So if we can, if we open
everything up and just
remove the API requirement altogether, uh,
for, for certain, you know, limited
things like just being able to find the,
uh, that that's
if we just open everything where you
can, anybody can get what is also in,
in the feed, then,
uh, that sort of solves a lot of problems,
makes it, makes it more widely available.
And, uh, yeah, I think that's,
that's definitely what we're going
to do here in the next few weeks.
Open is always better.
Perhaps the challenge there is that
if you have a public endpoint,
you need to implement some logic.
If you have an API key, you
can just block it easily.
And you, you have access control, but
imagine you have a peak of users.
It can be also, uh, you
know, some scraping engine.
It's, it's harder.
You need to add.
If someone is scraping, then could you
please just go download it from us?
We make it available.
The whole thing, no need to scrape.
Yeah.
See, that's what we've
tried to avoid by dump,
by doing a public feed
dump onto archive.org
is like dumping our whole DB or not
the whole one, but the feeds table.
Cause most people scrape in
order to get the feed URLs.
And so we've dumped everything publicly,
all the feed URLs so that we can,
so that if somebody starts scraping,
we just say, stop, stop doing that.
Just go download the CSV file.
It's all there.
It works.
It works amazingly well.
I'm so surprised and delighted by how
courteous everyone is, how, you know,
people ask before they start
hitting our, you know,
before they start hitting the
end point at all, you know,
Hey, I'm doing this.
This is okay.
I mean, it's, it's been really delightful.
Yeah, but you're right though, Alberto, we
are going to need some, some logic there.
And that's what I'm
thinking through before we
pull the trigger is
trying to make sure that
we can, uh, defend ourselves properly.
If somebody starts doing, you
know, getting some shenanigans.
It could be great if
you could send a 501 or
five or five zero zero response saying, go
download the whole dump of the feed.
Give them a link.
Yeah.
In the, in the 500.
Yes.
In the 500, right?
Why not?
Yeah.
That's, that's a great idea.
And so it's a little bit
more complicated, um,
rate limiting behind Cloudflare because
so Cloudflare allows you to rate limit
in their system, but it costs you money.
And it's one of those AWS type money costs
where you don't know in advance what it's
going to cost you because it's
like, okay, you can rate limit,
but every time the rate
limit kicks in, it's going
to cost you this many cents,
fractions of a cent per, per request.
And it's like, you're going
to put a debit card there.
A debit card is a thousand dollars limit.
Right.
Yeah.
It's the only way to go.
And so we're, uh, so, but, but then if
you're trying to rate limit on that backside
of Cloudflare, they, you, you
only get the, the source IP,
the true source IP address in a header.
And so I've got to put that
into some NGINX voodoo
so that we can actually like have some
sort of defense there for exactly
the reason you mentioned.
Yeah.
Well, that was hot.
No, no, it's probably, now
that everybody's gone.
Now that we're all alone,
just the four of us.
We'll start crumpling paper.
And I'll start it off by saying
this is a value for value project.
Check the entire podcastindex.org, which
includes, uh, your developer site.
And, uh, we also have a
podcastindex.social and
we gladly highlight all of the people who
are working with us at our new podcastapps.com
or podcastindex.org slash apps.
And if you go to podcastindex.org down
at the bottom, if you scroll down,
you'll see a big red donate button, uh,
also a QR code to send us some
Bitcoin through lightning or set up
a little subscription.
Uh, that's all we ask for is if
you're getting value out of it,
then just return it one way
or the other with your time,
your talent or your treasure.
And again, uh, big thanks to
Alberto and Ben who have, uh,
who have supported the project
financially more than anybody.
Uh, it's really, really appreciated.
And, but it's all every number, whatever
the value is, it's your number.
It's your value.
So who do we thank today, Dave?
Uh, the number for Thomas Carson,
uh, was $10 a month subscription.
Uh, thank you, thank you, Thomas.
There's no note.
Yeah.
Right.
And you can write notes.
We love reading the notes and just put that
in your, uh, in your transaction there.
Yeah.
And, uh, that, let's
see, I still don't have,
I'm going to do the repo and we're going
to, uh, we're going to put, uh, monthly
supporters in the re in the GitHub repo.
Yeah.
So we can do pull requests.
Donate through a pull request, please.
Uh, see, we've got 1111, uh, says,
uh, Hey guys, keep this anonymous,
a small contribution
for those doing the work as
podcasting builds back better.
Can I get some R2D2 karma?
Oh crap.
I wasn't expecting that.
Yeah.
Hold on a second.
Go do your search.
Yeah.
I got R2D2 karma.
Of course I do.
You've got karma.
Let's see what we got.
Uh, Oh, well we got 1111 last time.
And this, uh, this is 2222.
Oh, beautiful.
Yeah.
Uh, let's see.
Preserve, uh, from John lips,
uh, preserving podcasting.
Oh, here we go.
Preservingpodcasting.com is
forwarding to show my support.
Ooh, that's cool.
Hold on.
Put that forward to the
forward to us probably.
So let me see preserving podcasting.com.
Let me just check.
Hold on a second.
I love domain names.
Uh, Oh, I perverting podcasting.
Hold on a second.
Perverting.
Yeah.
That goes somewhere else.
Uh, it doesn't seem to be,
uh, that goes to anchor.
Preserving podcasting.
No, it doesn't go anywhere yet.
Maybe it hasn't worked it out yet.
Okay.
Uh, let's see.
But thank you.
The, uh, preserving podcast, preserve
pod, preserve podcasting.com.
Oh, you sent me down the
wrong hole here, man.
Hold on.
I was thinking perverting podcasting.com.
Yeah, it's better.
We should probably, yeah, we
should probably get that.
Preserve podcasting.
Uh, yes.
Reserve podcasting.com.
Go straight to podcast index.
Beautiful.
The waves in the proverbial
internet pond have
people sitting up and paying attention.
Podcasting 2.0 is a beacon
of hope that is sorely
needed for these dark days of winter.
Oh, um, you made fun of the
way I read things earlier.
I'm self-conscious.
Oh, I did not.
I'm so self-conscious.
I can't.
You're a pro.
You're inhibiting me.
Yes, that's right.
But that's it.
That's our group, man.
Sad puppy.
And thank you, Dreb Scott,
for popping that up just in time as I
view it here on my Podverse 3.0 beta.
I saw it.
The, uh, podcast, the, uh,
I fully expect sex robots at some point
in the image chapter aren't, Dreb.
Oh, hell yeah.
And know that just by, uh, participating
in our grand value for value scheme,
uh, with podcasting, you are
actually also supporting Dreb Scott.
What did you put him in for?
Five, five, uh, 5% on the cut?
Yeah, 5%.
Beautiful.
He's, he's a man who's getting paid.
That's right.
I mean, don't spend it
all in one place, Dreb.
Yeah.
Don't spend all, don't spend
all 75 cents of that at once.
What?
You're doing it on an annual basis.
Oh, okay.
An annual basis.
Somehow, somehow it is so exciting.
You know, you see the
Satoshis coming in or even
going out and it's an exciting feeling.
Uh, and I know you guys are
talking about it, Ben and Alberto.
And, uh, I know that, you know,
we have a long way to go before
we're ready for you most likely.
Uh, but it seems, it seems like, go ahead.
Yeah.
I was just going to say, Adam, uh,
you know, with RSS in particular,
kind of as a, as the
big thing, but even on the
little stuff, like you're,
you're connecting the virtue cycle,
the, the cycle of, you
know, value for value.
Um, and it's something that RSS needs like
in the, like as a, as a protocol, uh,
you know, that's where it was lacking.
It's just, uh, you know, the steward
to kind of take it to the next level.
And I just want to say thanks for that.
Like, but even on the small, like macro
or micro scale with each podcast, like,
you know, connecting all the,
all the players kicking out
the ones that don't need to be there that
are just kind of leeching, uh, you
know, on the transaction, so to speak.
Those are, you know,
that's super valuable.
And I think it's going to help
podcasting in general, uh, you know, as,
as new people
get in and they're not going to get, you
know, advertising sponsors probably.
And especially if they have,
they have content that advertisers
don't want to put anything
with, but if there's a message
that resonates with anybody, they,
they can see the value returned.
And so I think it's just, I just want
to say thanks for what you're doing.
Cause it's, it's sorely, sorely needed.
Um, and this isn't the only industry
where it's needed, but it's, it's, uh,
and it's you and it's
everybody on the Macedon.
I mean, it's, there's so many people
involved, but you know, you're,
you're help leading the
charge and, um, you know, we're grateful.
The, well, thank you.
And, uh, and, uh, and back at you and, uh,
our mission is really
to make it as easy as
possible for you to integrate.
I mean, I envision you've got your,
your customer who likes simple
and easy and all they have
is, you know, they just have their
wallet baked right into, uh,
to your system in their control panel.
They, they see that they can send it, uh,
you know, to their Venmo or, you know,
put it into dollars any way they want.
And it should just have a ticker.
And then of course you could do all,
you can add all kinds of
stuff to your statistics,
but that seems like such a logical fit.
Uh, and yeah, we have, go ahead, Dave.
Yeah.
We're going to have a
discussion about, uh, yes.
Promote this on Tuesday.
Yeah.
On Tuesday of next week, this
is all central time, uh,
my time Tuesday of next week at noon.
Yeah.
We're going to have a, uh, just
a, just a Q and a type thing.
And it's all, it's just
about L and pay because
L and pay is probably
the way that most people
at this moment will need to integrate,
um, lightning into their apps.
And so it's on my calendar,
believe it or not.
I won't add anything valuable to
the discussion, but, uh, no, no,
but I think it will be valuable
to see, because, you know, like
for, for you guys, it's, you know,
lightning is a, is a
difficult thing and it's difficult by
nest by necessity because it's, um,
you know, it involves
multi-layered money handling.
And so if you, what,
what the difficulty of lightning
comes in is having to open channels,
keep them funded, um, you
know, spin up a node.
It's a, it's, there's a lot of complexity.
Peering, routings, fees.
Yes.
All that.
And so, and all that stuff
can bite you in the butt.
So, uh, what, uh, Garma said on, um,
on the mastermind is he communicate
with Tim and I didn't know that.
I didn't know this.
I thought Tim was still
working on inbound keys in.
No, I guess he's already
got it working evidently.
And so like the way that
it looks to me is that
a host like RSS.com could
replicate an L and pay system.
Yeah.
Basically call the L and pay API, spin
up a wallet and it has inbound keys in,
and you don't have to worry about the
liquidity and all that kind of stuff.
The reporting is almost
built in all web API.
It's all there.
Yeah.
I think that is a pretty, that's,
that could be really strong.
Cause that means you could put in,
you could spin up a wallet and
put that information directly
in the feed and then not have to
host any of that jazz yourself.
But the cool thing though,
is I think once we,
this is sort of going to be like a, you
know, Vulcan mind meld on Tuesday to
where we try to, uh, anybody has,
you know, questions and information
and all that kind of stuff.
We can just brain share this stuff.
Then if over the next time period,
whatever time period this is,
if we can figure out how
all this stuff works and figure out
that it's solid and prove it out,
then that could be a real option for,
for hosting companies to, to go,
to be able to integrate lightning without
having all the complexity of
having to go learn lightning.
Possibly.
Yeah.
Great.
I don't know.
Yeah.
It would be great if you, if you, if you
guys could make it or all, all of the,
uh, RSS tool and dye companies
can, if, if all, you know,
if everyone can join in because, oh yeah.
And you should probably make it say
upfront, Dave, now I'm thinking about it,
say this will be recorded and record it.
So the comic strip blogger
knows it's being recorded.
And if he doesn't want to be
on it, then no, I'm, I'm,
I'm sensitive to people's privacy.
So it's never a problem.
You just got to say it.
And so it doesn't want, you know,
then they can take their own action.
Yeah.
But yeah, I, I'd like to see more of that
because, and there'll be other players.
Uh, I hope Graham's going to join, um, from
voltage, you know, cause what we're kind
of starting to get good at is, uh, is
kind of orchestrating a little bit,
you know, it's like, okay, we've got
him over here and can you talk to him?
And, you know, it's like, and then we have
some API stuff and some glue and, and the
collaboration is really
beautiful to watch.
So we, we just, uh, we'd love
as much as we can get much,
much collaboration one way or the other.
Yeah.
We love watching it too.
Sorry, Dave, didn't mean
to speak over you there.
No, you're fine.
No, I got high hopes for it.
I think, I think, uh, I think L the L and
pay model is the, is the way forward.
Um, I really do because there's just,
otherwise the complexity is just
a little too much to overcome.
Yeah.
I think, yeah, I agree with you.
And it was, it would,
it was another one of those
fortuitous things that we bumped into
Tim is, is just like, Oh, okay.
This is, and it wasn't his first words.
Like, Oh, I've been waiting for
business people to show up.
He's like, I've been sitting
around with this thing for a year.
Like no one's doing anything with it.
Yeah.
We were, we were like, how
are you, how do you monetize?
And he's like, I don't, I don't
know how, I don't know what to do.
You know?
Well, we basically, if, you
know, if it all works out,
we've given him a way to monetize,
which is the same we're doing
for the app developers.
Let me ask you this,
uh, Ben, what do y'all,
this has been in the back of my mind too.
At least so I, uh, in, in the industry
that I'm in, uh, for my day job,
the software vendors
that we have almost to
almost all of them have
sort of an early adopter beta type, you
know, program that you can get in where
you say, you know, our company is a,
is sort of a bleeding edge company and
we want to test all the new software.
We know there's going to be bugs.
We know it's going to screw things up.
We want to have the newest and we want
to test the new stuff before it's ready,
but I don't see any podcast
hosting companies that
offer that type of thing where it's like,
okay, you have a beta group who are
the bleeding edge guys that are like,
we want, we want the new stuff.
We want the new features
before anybody else gets it.
And we're willing for our
stuff to break a deal.
Do y'all have, is that a
possibility to have something
like that where you could test this stuff?
Yeah, we could sandbox maybe a little bit.
What we've done in practice in the past is
just rolled something out and called it a
beta and let it get beat up by our users.
And that's how we have
really kind of optimized
the easy and simple aspects of things.
But for the more sophisticated
things, Alberto,
let me have you answer on that regard.
Yeah.
I mean, I think the only issue, at least
for us, is human bandwidth, right?
It's just, we have 12 people
in the team, three engineers.
I don't know, just in 2020, we had
over 1,200 improvements, bug fixes,
and also we rolled out new features.
But if we start to have
features plug, beta testing,
we need to really increase the team size.
And this also implies creating
new processes, right?
We were talking about
that at the beginning.
So 12 people is a good number.
But if we double the team, then we
are going to go slow for a while.
So it's just a matter of human
resources at the moment for us.
We would love to start
to have a beta program
with new features just for a few selected.
I really like how you approach that.
That's the best approach I've heard.
I'm sure other people do this,
but just you're verbalizing it
beautifully and totally on board.
Understand it, get it.
And I know you're going to get there
in your own time and it'll be right.
Yeah.
He's got a lot of practice on me.
I sit there and say, let's do this.
Right.
It's like Adam and Dave.
I know.
I can tell the dynamics.
Exactly.
Yeah.
Today, we had a call
before our conversation.
And well, Ben told me, oh, I love the new
player of the new podcast users page.
I love it.
It's new.
We have to roll it out in
the next couple of weeks.
He told me, can we show a
chapter from podcast index?
I said, we don't have them yet.
I always liked it.
Yeah.
Go faster.
That's right.
Alberto, he really is.
He's world class in so many things.
And one of them is just managing
expectations and setting a proper, you know,
speed, you know, max speed is what it is.
It's not, you know, fantasy speed.
Yeah.
I think that in the IT world,
I mean, like programming, ops,
all of the IT in general, there
is a severe lack of soft skills.
There always has been.
And if you, I mean, if you
have, it's not enough,
if you want to be successful in IT,
it is not enough to just
have a bunch of tech chops.
You have to have, you
have to have some chops,
but the soft skills are
way more important.
That's where, that's where you can actually
make something technological make sense
and work for people in the real world.
It's, it's always been a problem.
Wouldn't agree more.
Well, gentlemen, uh, go ahead.
No, I said, I, Dave should have
said, does that make sense?
I was expecting you.
All right.
It takes a foreigner to
put you in your place.
Now I know how it works.
Yeah.
You just, you got to start
speaking Dutch to me.
No, shut up.
Alberto and Ben, thank you both
so much for joining us today.
And I wish you a lot of success.
You've, you're at a magical moment, not
only in, uh, in podcasting, I think,
but, uh, certainly in your own company's,
uh, growth and, uh, and evolvement,
evolvement, development,
uh, and congratulations.
Whenever I see any kind of
entrepreneur succeeding is beautiful.
Really, really, really love seeing that.
And, uh, you know, whatever you guys
need, um, we're, we're just a hop away.
Yeah.
Well, likewise, I mean, we, uh,
we feel a kinship to a lot of the things
that you guys are pushing forward.
So, um, we definitely feel like we need
to amplify, uh, all of those things.
Very cool.
Thank you so much.
Oh, no, you're more than welcome.
Dave, anything for you
for, uh, the round table?
Oh, yeah.
Uh, I'm about to get a cup of coffee.
I'm about to go with coffee
number five for the day.
I'm getting ready for part.
We put you to sleep, man.
No, no, no.
I'm fired up.
I mean, so it's reversed.
It's the ADHD, man.
I got to calm it down.
All right, everybody.
We will be back next week with another
meeting of the board of directors and,
uh, we'll do it right
here on podcasting 2.0.
See you then.
You hope you have been
listening to podcasting 2.0.
Visit podcastindex.org
for more information.
Podcasts are cool.